A Finding Aid to the Dorothy Lubell Feigin Papers, 1923-1969, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Dorothy Lubell Feigin papers
1923-1969
Archives of American Art
Feigin, Dorothy Dee Lubell, 1902-1969
AAA.feigdoro
Archival Resource Key
0.6 Linear feet
The scattered papers of painter and educator Dorothy Lubell Feigin measure 0.6 linear feet and date from 1923 to 1969. Found are sketches by Waldo Peirce, biographical material, correspondence, photographs of Feigin and of works of art, scattered printed material, and two mixed-media scrapbooks. Also found are materials regarding the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors including correspondence, exhibition records, printed material, and reports.
Biographical / Historical
Dorothy Lubell Feigin (1902-1969) was a painter, printmaker, and educator in New York City, New York. Feigin studied at the Art Students League and was an active member of the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors.
Scope and Contents
The scattered papers of painter and educator Dorothy Lubell Feigin measure 0.6 linear feet and date from 1923 to 1969. Found are sketches by Waldo Peirce, biographical material, correspondence, photographs of Feigin and of works of art, scattered printed material, and two mixed-media scrapbooks. Also found are materials regarding the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors including correspondence, exhibition records, printed material, and reports.
Conditions Governing Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C., Research Center. Microfilmed materials must be consulted on microfilm. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Dr. Simeon Feigin, Dorothy Feigin's son, donated material in 1971. Additional material was donated in 1974 by Edith Bry, a close friend of Feigin and a colleague and fellow member of the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors.
Existence and Location of Copies
Portions of the collection are available on 35mm microfilm reel N69-128 at Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the material described in the container inventory does not reflect the arrangement of the collection on microfilm
Arrangement
Due to the small size of this collection the papers are arranged as one series.
Related Materials
The Archives of American Art also holds the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors records, 1940-1996, and the Edith Bry papers, 1914-1969.
Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Graphic artists -- New York (State) -- New York; Educators -- New York (State) -- New York; Women artists; Women painters; Women printmakers; Women educators; Scrapbooks; Printmakers -- New York (State) -- New York; Peirce, Waldo, 1884-1970; Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors
- Dorothy Lubell Feigin Papers, 1923-1969; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Scope and Contents
  Series includes illustrated envelopes addressed to Feigin by Waldo Peirce and a print by Gusta and Bertman Hartman. Biographical materials include certificates and professional degrees for Dorothy and Solomon Feigin. Correspondence is with galleries and institutions including the Academy of Allied Artists, Argent Galleries, City of New York Board of Education, the New Gallery Art Club, and the National Academy of Design. Also found are scattered letters from family. Photographs depict Feigin, Feigin in her classroom with students, and works of art. Printed material consists of scattered clippings. Two mixed-media scrapbooks contain letters, photographs of works of art, exhibition announcements, and clippings. One scrapbook is dismantled.
  Also found are records concerning the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, focusing on when Feigin served as treasurer of the organization. These files include correspondence from artists including Reuben Tam and Harold Weston concerning membership; printed material from exhibitions and clippings; an exhibition file including photographs for the 17th annual exhibition (1957); and treasurer reports.
  - Artwork, 1954-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Material, 1926-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1924-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, 1950-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Photographs, Feigin and Others, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Works of Art, circa 1950s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Printed Material, Clippings, 1941-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook, Dismantled, 1924-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Scrapbook, 1923-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)